<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello, Bee Planet</title><link>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/hello-bee-planet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/hello-bee-planet/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong> — The wiki is for structured, evergreen guidance. The blog is for timely updates, experiments, and behind-the-scenes notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-a-blog">Why a blog?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The wiki has a stable house style and taxonomy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The blog lets us move quickly – new findings, hornet alerts, or field tips.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We can decide later which posts “graduate” into full wiki articles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="what-to-expect">What to expect&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Brief posts – a couple of minutes to read.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plain language – bright, breezy, practical.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-linking into relevant wiki pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you’d like to suggest a topic, head to the contact page and say hello.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bee Line: Why the world’s future still hangs on a hum</title><link>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/the-bee-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/the-bee-line/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Bee Line: Why the world’s future still hangs on a hum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bees are more than honey-makers - they are the quiet workforce holding our food systems together. This piece is my line in the sand and a statement for what I stand for at Bee Planet Connection. Bee Planet Connection will challenge orthodoxies, cheer on good practice, and call out the lazy myths that keep us stuck. Think Sunday paper essay meets a straight-talking op-ed. Let’s talk about why bees - honeybees and their wild cousins - still sit at the centre of a global story about food, culture, climate, and what we value. And yes, we’ll be upfront about honey - celebrating it while also being honest about the trade-offs and ethics that come with loving something we take from.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bee Line: Why the World’s Future Still Hangs on a Hum</title><link>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/the-bee-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.beeplanetconnection.org/blog/the-bee-line/</guid><description>&lt;p>I live in West London, where planes stitch contrails over Kew and foxes treat the back garden like the A4 at rush hour. On mild evenings you’ll still catch a low, contented hum above the rosemary and thyme. It’s the sort of sound you only notice once you’ve learned to listen for it—an everyday music that says the neighbourhood is still ticking over. When that sound fades, life itself gets scratchy. Food gets dearer. Harvests wobble. Whole ecosystems misfire.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>